You can't beat a holiday, but would you ever consider going away for just one day?
没有比度假更棒的了，但你是否考虑过只出去一天？
Extreme day trips are a new trend that squeeze international adventure into just 24 hours.
极限一日游是一种新趋势，它将跨国旅行冒险压缩在仅仅24小时内。
It might sound exhausting, but for lots of people, the appeal lies in time efficiency, budget-friendly prices and the excitement of going somewhere and doing something completely new.
这听起来可能很累人，但对许多人来说，其吸引力在于时间效率、经济实惠的价格以及去某个地方做全新事情带来的兴奋感。
It's possible to zip to cities in your own country to experience new culture, food and geography without ever leaving 'home', though many European extreme day-trippers go abroad.
尽管许多欧洲的极限一日游者选择出国，但仅仅是在国内旅行也是可能的，快速穿梭于各个城市，体验新的文化、美食和地理，而无需真正离开"家"。
Monica Stott, a travel blogger from the UK, has taken day trips to Reykjavik in Iceland, Milan in Italy and Lisbon in Portugal, all without staying overnight.
来自英国的旅行博主莫妮卡·斯托特曾前往冰岛雷克雅未克、意大利米兰和葡萄牙里斯本进行一日游，全都没有过夜。
It all started for her when she flew over to Ireland for work meetings.
这一切始于她飞往爱尔兰参加工作会议。
She told the BBC, "I'd quite often pop over for a one or two-hour meeting and come home.
她告诉BBC："我经常飞过去开一两个小时的会然后回家。
Then I realised I could stay and make a full day of it."
然后我意识到我可以去那充分利用一整天。"
Social media groups advertising extreme day trips are now booming.
宣传极限一日游的社交媒体群组现在正如火如荼地发展。
These groups offer a supportive community for like-minded travellers and are packed with tips and destination ideas.
这些群组为志同道合的旅行者提供了一个互助的社区，并充满了小贴士和目的地创意。
However, it's not all fun and games.
然而，它并不全是乐趣和消遣。
Hours of the day can easily be taken up with long airport transfers, traffic jams, and in many big cities, there isn't enough time to see everything you want to.
一天中的几个小时很容易被漫长的机场通勤、交通堵塞所占据，而且在许多大城市，没有足够的时间去看所有你想看的东西。
Critics also point to the environmental cost.
批评者还指出了环境成本。
Flying significantly contributes to global emissions and makes carbon-neutral air travel aims, such as the UK's Jet Zero, much less likely to succeed.
飞行极大地增加了全球排放量，并使碳中和航空旅行目标（如英国的"喷气零排放"）更不可能实现。
If other forms of transport can be used, such as trains, that can be a better alternative for the environment.
如果可以乘坐其他交通工具，比如火车，那对环境来说是更好的选择。
Train stations are often located in city centres, so you can be right in the heart of the city in much less time.
火车站通常位于市中心，因此你可以用更少的时间直达城市中心。
So, if you're tempted, pack light, plan smart and consider the best way to travel for the environment and limited time you have.
所以，如果你心动了，轻装上阵，聪明规划，并考虑在你有限的时间里，选择对环境最好的旅行方式。